Where will you be?
The Day After Tomorrow is a science fiction, thriller,
adventure film directed by Roland Emmerich.
After paleoclimatologist Jack Hall is largely ignored by UN officials when presenting his environmental concerns about the beginning of a new
Ice Age, his research proves true when a superstorm develops, setting off catastrophic natural disasters throughout the world.
Trying to get to his son, Sam, who is trapped in New York City with his friend Laura and
others, Jack and his crew must travel to get to Sam before it's too late.
Jack Hall, played by Dennis Quaid.
Sam Hall, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Laura Chapman, played by Emmy Rossum.
Jason Evans, played by Dash Mihok.
Frank Harris, played by Jay O. Sanders.
Dr. Lucy Hall, played by Sela Ward.
The Day After Tomorrow is a 2004 American science fiction disaster film co-written, co-produced, and directed by Roland Emmerich, based on the 1999 book The
Coming Global Superstorm by Art Bell and Whitley Strieber, and starring Dennis Quaid, Jake Gyllenhaal, Sela Ward, Emmy Rossum, and Ian Holm.
It depicts catastrophic climatic effects following the disruption of the North Atlantic Ocean circulation, in
which a series of extreme weather events usher in climate change and lead to a new ice age.
Originally slated for release in the summer of 2003, The Day After Tomorrow premiered in Mexico City on May
17, 2004, and was theatrically released in the United States by 20th Century Fox on May 28.
It was a commercial success, grossing $552 million worldwide against a production
budget of $125 million, becoming the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2004.
Filmed in Montreal, it was the highest-grossing Hollywood
film made in Canada at its time of release.
The film was nominated for Best Science Fiction Film and
Best Special Effects at the Saturn Awards.
The film explores themes of new york city, philadelphia,
pennsylvania, saving the world, scotland, climate change.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.